1. List the Customer Name (first and last concatenated) aliased as Customer Name, Ship Date, and Order Date for Order 451:	


SELECT firstname ||' '|| lastname AS "Customer Name" , orderdate, shipdate
FROM customers c INNER JOIN orders o
ON c.id = o.customerid
INNER JOIN order_details od
ON o.id = od.orderId
AND od.orderid = 451;


2. List all product names aliased as Product (only once per vendor) and the vendor’s name aliased as Vendor, who sells the product, sort by the product name	


SELECT DISTINCT p.name AS "Product", v.name AS "Vendor"
FROM products p INNER JOIN product_vendors pv
ON p.id = pv.productId
INNER JOIN vendors v
ON pv.vendorId = v.id
ORDER BY 1

3.  List the customer’s name, product name, retail price and discount amount (see aliases below) for all items on order 486 that have been discounted (where quoted price is less than retail price)


SELECT DISTINCT firstname, lastname, name AS product, retailprice, retailprice - quotedprice AS "Discounted Amt."
FROM customers c INNER JOIN orders o  
ON c.id = o.customerId
INNER JOIN order_details od
ON o.id = od.orderId
INNER JOIN products p
ON p.id = od.productId 
AND o.id = 486 
AND retailprice - quotedprice != 0 


4. List the product name and vendor id for all products that we have purchased from more than one vendor, sort this one on product name (Hint: you’ll need to use a Self-Join and an additional INNER JOIN to solve, see above for reference) Don’t forget to remove any duplicates.

SELECT DISTINCT p.name AS product, pv1.vendorid AS vendorid     
FROM product_vendors pv1 INNER JOIN product_vendors pv2
ON pv1.productId = pv2.productId
AND pv1.vendorId != pv2.vendorId
INNER JOIN products p
ON p.id = pv1.productId
ORDER BY 1 	 


TRUE it is valid SQL syntax to inner join the employees and customers tables
where Province = City






